All right, here we are in the IDE again and I've just created a class with you appropriately named fun with strings
That's what we're going to do. And what I'll just do it. I'll just go ahead and just create a string class as you saw
It's in Java line. That's why we don't need to import it right. So let's say string and I'll just call it for example data
And let's just say new string. I told you this is the first way of using it, but I just used the
Direct way that is without you even using the key one new and I'll just say for example Java is
one
still in
pretty 26
All right, make sure it is
And we just go ahead and say it's out and just say data
You know, this would just be a string created when you'll say data plus equal to but guess what we even have a method
That is going to get
Right, because it's string right lots of utility methods
So why do we just need to use the generic plus equal to we have its own method contract and just put in a
String that would be concatenated it takes a string on human as a Java is still in pretty 26 will stop
It's still
Why you need used
All right, and then we'll just go ahead and then I'll do a sound and we'll just say this time
Now again, what is the output that you'll expect in line number nine take a minute pause the speed you and think about it
And then see what your guess is if it's right or wrong
But I tell you it would still be Java is fun still in 2026
Why because we did not assign or reassign remember that that what we did on the wild bull drive whenever you operate
Please remember to assign or reassign. Otherwise. It would just be a new object created couple of
Objects created in the scp string concert pool, but you'll get the older value. See you should still get Java is fun
Still in pretty good reasons. That's not this not the updated value
This two times first for this one the next with this one until you do
Something like this you reassign and see the warning goes away as well
What was the warning? IntelliJ was telling this about you hover on this tells you result of string or concaten is ignored
It was put in the scp, but it is ignored because it's still referring to the older value. Right? Otherwise
Now you should get the updated value. It's on this
Yeah, it's still widely used
Right
So similarly different methods here some utility methods. I'll just say
If you just directly do a system of print Ln and say data dot to lower case or to upper case
See
This would directly print the updated value that is in upper case, but data would still hold the older value because we did not reassign
But here we'll get the updated value
Right
Only
Temporality
Why because if you're still print data after this it would still hold the older title case value. Let's go on around this
It has Java is one still in 2026. It's still widely used. You see everything in capitals
Just with that one utility method to upper case next so then we have again data dot
two
Or a method called catat
Right takes an integer and gives you the character and academics
Let's say a stop
This time you don't need to reassign because it's returning the character not a string
What is it say cannot resolve method catat in string? Okay
Let's say what is that
Yeah, it's there. I don't know what happened with intelligent. We're using it the same way
I'll just go ahead and run this and does give you
S why because strings like it is start with index 0 so 0 1 2 3 4 by 6. It gave us on screen
Similarly, we have sub strings right if you want to get a string with a string you can just go ahead and say
data dot
Substring
And x integer parameter that is in start where do you want to start from I'll say I want to start from
five
Until end see says big in index and then if you say a print and then you'll still get the older value
If you're not reassign and it creates one more object in the scp the scp is getting piled up
By now you might be wondering what sort of efficient utilization of string memory is this when we
Unintentionally inadvertently create more objects in the string constant. What sort of what kind of
efficient utilization of memory? This is I'll get to that in a moment
And it is then when it will make more sense but for now please
Remember to reassign or directly put this in a print telling
If you don't want to reassign or assign
Now you should get what you want
See it just gives you is fun
Starting with the index 6 sorry the index 5 see is fun in 26. It's still why you use and there's a
Different version of substring which takes two arguments in start in the end because you might want to have a requirement
You want to get a string within the string from start to end. I'll say two two
See run this
See is fun
Just this from five to 12. Let's see
0123 for five right it starts from s right. Sorry is that is
I 0123 for obvious and then it goes to 12 but in start in substring it's zero based in
And it's one base you need to be here for that is it starts counting from one that is one two three four five six seven eight nine
Ten eleven two L. So you just get from this to this including the space. That's what you saw is fun with a spacey
The tiny spacey so end end is one based then we have a utility method called
if you
Want to tokenize your string right if you want to break your string so you have a great utility method and
That is I'll say data dot split
So I'm properly called it takes the delimiter as a string
Right in regular expression and I want to break it as space whenever there is a space and
What might be the return type of split again?
Pause this video think about it come up with a guess then resume the review and then map it with what I see
And you write it returns a string array what else would it have been a string array with different tokens broken at space
So I just say string
Why use
And put this as an array
See there is one and thanks to Java five enhanced problem. You can just go ahead and travel is that answering string
while you
Values and then go ahead and print that
That should print all tokens. I just put in a print here. I'll say after
breaking
string
Why don't you
Send the see Java is fun still in toilet six. It's still widely used
But guess what all of these would be created as new objects in the string on still pool
So that whenever you have to reuse the same value, it would not be created again
But the scp by now is just getting accumulated unnecessarily
So you're right in thinking so I'm getting to that right
So at this point that is what string value value system not a print telling it just got us all the values
That were used that were broken with the method split
Right that is the string tokenizer how it tokenizes your string
I have a question for you
I'll just put that in the exercise based on this what we are currently discussing have an eye on that so
But that is how the string class who works now on to the other point
Right, what is what is what is the efficient utilization of the string memory really about it?
Because the moment we do an operation the moment we do an operation we inadvertently
End up creating more objects in the string constant pool even more than what we require what we need
What is that hype all about immutability scb?
Let's have a look at and a couple of more classes in the next week